Barbara and Howard Fussiner collection on Denise Levertov M2241
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Barbara and Howard Fussiner collection on Denise Levertov
1951-circa 1997
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Fussiner, Barbara
Fussiner, Howard
Levertov, Denise, 1923-1997
Goodman, Mitchell
M2241
0.75 Linear Feet (1 manuscript box and 1 half box)
Biographical / Historical
Barabara (née Bank) Fussiner and her husband Howard Fussiner were friends of poet Denise Levertov. Barbara and Denise met in New York in 1948 through Mitch Goodman's brother Howard. Barbara went on to work as the director of the Children's Preschool in New Haven, Connecticut. Howard was a painter and later worked as Souther Connecticut State University as a professor of art. Denise and Mitch wed in 1947 and divorced in 1975.
Scope and Contents
Materials consist of correspondence between the Fussiners and Denise Levertov and Mitchell Goodman, mostly incoming correspondece to the Fussiners from Denise and/or Mitch. Letters and cards from a few other individuals can be found in the collection as well.
General
Denise also signed her name as Denny, Den, D. She also addressed Barbara and Howard Fussiner as B and H.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased by Stanford Libraries in 2017. Accession 2017-190.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
American literature -- 20th century; Poets, American; Fussiner, Barbara; Fussiner, Howard; Levertov, Denise, 1923-1997; Goodman, Mitchell
- Letter from Mitch Goodman (?) and Denny to Barbara (nee Bank), 1951-01-23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letter from Mitch Goodman (?) to Barbara (nee Bank), 1951-11-26 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letter from D to Barbara (nee Bank), 1959-07-18 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letter from D and Mitch to Barbara (nee Bank), 1959-07-23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letter from Mitch to Nell (Blaine?), 1959-09-28 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letter from D to Barbara (nee Bank), 1959-10-26 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letter from Mitch to Barbara (nee Bank), 1959-12-09 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letter from Mitch to Barbara (nee Bank), 1959-12-17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letter from Mitch to Barbara (nee Bank), 1959-12-18 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letter from Mitch to Barbara (nee Bank), 1959-12-19 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letter from D to Barbara (nee Bank), 1960-02-14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letter from Mitch to Barbara (nee Bank), 1960-12-27 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letter from D to Barbara (nee Bank), 1961-09-14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letter from Beatrice Levertoff to Barbara Fussiner, 1963-08-29 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1963-09-11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letter from Beatrice Levertoff to Barbara, 1963-11-09 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Postcard from Barbara and Howard to D and Mitch, 1964-04-04 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letter from D and Mitch to Barbara and Howard, 1964-06-02 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letter from Beatrice Levertoff to Barbara, 1964-12-08 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letter from D to Howard and Peter (?), 1965-02-03 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letter from Beatrice Levertoff to Barbara, 1965-08-05 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1965-08-08 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letter from D, Mitch and Nick to Barbara, Howard, and David, 1965-08-13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letter from Beatrice Levertoff to Barbara, 1965-09-28 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Postcard from D to Barbara and Howard, 1965-11-06 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letter from Beatrice Levertoff to Barbara, 1966-05-18 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letter from D and Mitch to Barbara and Howard, 1966-07-27 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letter from Mitch to Barbara and Howard, 1967-08-04 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Postcard from Barbara and Howard to D and Mitch, 1967-08-31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ink drawings of trees, in an envelope from D Levertov to H Fussiner, 1973-04-05 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letter from Mitch to Barbara and Howard, 1973-06-29 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letter from Beatrice Levertoff to Barbara, 1973-08-12 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1973-09-05 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Postard from D to Barbara and Howard, 1974-02-11 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letter from D to Howard, 1974-10-27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letter from Mitch to Howard, 1975-11-10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1976-12-06 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Postcard from D to Barbara and Howard, 1977-03-08 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Postcard from D to Barbara and Howard, 1977-04-05 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letter from Lupita Abascal (?) to Howard, 1977-07-27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Postcard from D to Barbara and Howard, 1979-03-11 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Postcard from D to Barbara and Howard, 1979-03-24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Postcard from D to Barbara, 1979-10-09 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Postcard from Steve to D, 1980-03-02 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Postcard from Barbara to D, 1980-12-28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Card from Carl to D, 1982-01-20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letter from Mich to Barbara, 1982-10-05 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Card from Paul to D, 1983-03-11 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letter from D to Barbara, 1983-04-22 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1984-07-05 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Postcard from D to Barbara and Howard, 1985-07-26 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letter from D to Barbara, 1985-08-15 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letter with postcard from D to Barbara and Howard, 1987-01-11 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Postcard from D to Barbara and Howard, 1987-06-30 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letters from D to Barbara, to Howard, 1987-07-17 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Postcard from D to Barbara and Howard, 1987-02-28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letter from D to Howard, 1987-11-17 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Card with poem from D to Barbara and Howard, 1987-11-18 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter from Carol Ann Russell to D, 1987-11-18 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Postcard fro D to Barbara, 1987-12-10 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter from D to Barbara, 1988-02-29 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter from D to Howard and Barbara, 1988-07-26 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Postcard from Barbara and Howard to D, 1988-08-02 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Telegram from D to Howard, 1988-11-09 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter from D to Barbara, 1988-11-29 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Postcard continued as letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1989-03-12 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1989-06-02 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Postcard from D to Barbara and Howard, 1989-09-27 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1989-10-10 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter with a Monet brochure from D to Howard, 1989-10-24 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Postcard from D to Barbara and Howard, 1989-11-21 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Card from D to Barbara, 1990-01-04 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Postcard from Sara to D, 1990-04-25 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Postcard fro D to Barbara and Howard, 1992-02-02 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letter from Mitch to Barbara and Howard, 1992-02-25 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Card from D to Howard, 1992-05-18 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1992-10-01 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letter, including copy of additional letter, from D to Howard, 1993-01-16 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letter from Mitch to Barbara and Howard, 1993-02-06 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letter from D to Barbara, 1993-02-18 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letter from Mitch to Barbara and Howard, 1993-04-12 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letter from Mitch to Barbara and Howard, 1993-05-12 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Postcard from D to Barbara and Howard, 1993-11-25 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1993-11-30 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Card with incomplete letter from D to Barbara, 1994-01-12 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1994-11-03 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1994-11-25 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1995-04-17 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Incomplete letter on card to Barbara and Howard, 1995-06-03 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Postcard from D to Barbara, 1995-06-28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letter with poem (draft?? "Le Motif" from D to Barbara and Howard, 1995-08-22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Postcard in an envelope from D to Barbara and Howard, 1995-08-22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Postcard with poems from D to Barbara and Howard, 1995-09-07 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1995-09-26 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1995-10-01 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letter from Mitch to Barbara, 1995-09-07 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1995-11-07 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1996-01-20 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Partial letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1996-02-24 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Set of three postards from D to Howard, 1996-03-21 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Postcard from D to Howard, 1996-05-20 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1996-07-12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, 1996-08-12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Incomplete letter from D to Barbara, 1997-01-13 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letter from D to Howard, 1997-03-03 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letter from D to Barbara, 1997-06-18 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letter from D to Howard, 1997-07-07 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letter from D to Barbara, 1997-08-14 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letter from D to Barbara, 1960's-05-27 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter from D to Barbara, 1960's-08-20 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter from D to Barbara (nee Bank), 1960's-10-09 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter from Mitch to Barbara (nee Bank), 2-11 prior to 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Card from D to Saul Fussiner, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Postcard from D to Barbara and Howard, 5-4 (no year) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Postcard from D to Barbara and Howard, 5-26 (no year) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter from D to Barbara, 6-13 (no year) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter from D to Barbara, 7-19 (no year) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Postcard from Barbara and Howard (never sent) to D, 7-19 (no year) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Postcard from D to Barbara and Howard, 8-5 (no year) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter from D to Barbara, 8-10 (no Year) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Postcard from D to Barbara, 8-25 (no year) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter from D to Barbara, 9-9 (no year) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Card with postcard from D to Barbara and Howard, 12-19 (no year) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Set of four postcards from D to Howard, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter from D to Barbara, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Card from D to Howard, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Card from D to Barbara, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Card from D to Howard, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Card from D to Barbara, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter with hand drawn driving directions from D to Barbara and Howard, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter from D to Barbara (nee Bank), no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter from Mitch to Barbara and Howard, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter from Nik (?) (or Mitch) to Barbara and Howard, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Card from D to Howard, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Postcard from D and Mitch to Barbara, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Postcard from D to Carlene, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letter from D to Barbara and Howard, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Partial letter from D, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Tribute to Denise Levertov, 1923-1997 (Half-box 2, Folder 1)
- Ephemera (Half-box 2, Folder 1)
- Cancelled envelopes (Half-box 2, Folder 1)
- Negative strips from Seattle trip; photo of person holding snake; slide of "The Artist's Studio" from the Balt. Museum of Art (Half-box 2, Folder 2)